<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Capoeira on Capoeria Axè</title>
    <link>http://capoeirafirenze.com/en/capoeira/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Capoeira on Capoeria Axè</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>it-IT</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://capoeirafirenze.com/en/capoeira/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>http://capoeirafirenze.com/en/capoeira/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://capoeirafirenze.com/en/capoeira/history/</guid>
      <description>The Origins Capoeira is a Brazilian martial art. However, this definition succeeds only partly in defining the peculiar nature of this discipline. The African origins are to be traced back to the slave period, when different ethnic groups were uprooted from their African homelands and forcefully transferred to Brazil, to be used in the plantations, mines and houses of their owners.
A fighting and personal defense technique, Capoeira became a true instrument of defense for the slaves, giving them the opportunity to respond to the violence they endured, and to escape and reach the “Quilombos” - the Republics set up and organized by runaway slaves, where Capoeira was freely practiced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practise</title>
      <link>http://capoeirafirenze.com/en/capoeira/practise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://capoeirafirenze.com/en/capoeira/practise/</guid>
      <description>The Spirit of Capoeira Capoeira provides a precise and complete athletic preparation which allows the capoerista to use all the various movements during the game - basic, offensive, defensive and acrobatic movements. The comparison with other martial arts emerges from the common use of certain movements in such a manner as to confront the opponent, but the originality consists in following the rhythm of the instruments and transforming the encounter into a moment of true creativity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>